<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy Systems | Wenqi Cui</title>
    <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/tag/energy-systems/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wenqi-cui.github.io/tag/energy-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Energy Systems</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 08:00:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/media/icon_hud58c95a75c7ebfda2aff7ad5a2db624a_15115_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Energy Systems</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/tag/energy-systems/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Power System Dynamics and Transients: A Frequency Domain Approach</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/fourier-transient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/fourier-transient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dynamics of power grids are governed by a large number of nonlinear ordinary differential equations (ODEs). To safely operate the system, operators need to check that the states described by this set of ODEs stay within prescribed limits after various faults. Limited by the size and stiffness of the ODEs, current numerical integration techniques are often too slow to be useful in real-time or large-scale resource allocation problems. In addition, detailed system parameters are often not exactly known. Machine learning approaches have been proposed to reduce the computational efforts, but existing methods generally suffer from overfitting and failures to predict unstable behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes a novel framework for power system dynamic predictions by learning in the frequency domain. The intuition is that although the system behavior is complex in the time domain, there are relatively few dominate modes in the frequency domain. Therefore, we learn to predict by constructing neural networks with Fourier transform and filtering layers. System topology and fault information are encoded by taking a multi-dimensional Fourier transform, allowing us to leverage the fact that the trajectories are sparse both in time and spatial (across different buses) frequencies. We show that the proposed approach does not need detailed system parameters, speeds up prediction computations by orders of magnitude and is highly accurate for different fault types.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Safe Reinforcement Learning for Voltage Control</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/safe-rl-voltage-pscc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/safe-rl-voltage-pscc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inverter-based distributed energy resources provide the possibility for fast time-scale voltage control by quickly adjusting their reactive power. The power-electronic interfaces allow these resources to realize almost arbitrary control law, but designing these decentralized controllers is nontrivial. Reinforcement learning (RL) approaches are becoming increasingly popular to search for policy parameterized by neural networks. It is difficult, however, to enforce that the learned controllers are safe, in the sense that they may introduce instabilities into the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes a safe learning approach for voltage control. We prove that the system is guaranteed to be exponentially stable if each controller satisfies certain Lipschitz constraints. The set of Lipschitz bound is optimized to enlarge the search space for neural network controllers. We explicitly engineer the structure of neural network controllers such that they satisfy the Lipschitz constraints by design. A decentralized RL framework is constructed to train local neural network controller at each bus in a model-free setting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyapunov-Regularized Reinforcement Learning for Power System Transient Stability</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/lyapunov-regularized-reinforcement-learning-for-power-system-transient-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/lyapunov-regularized-reinforcement-learning-for-power-system-transient-stability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Transient stability of power systems is becoming increasingly important because of the growing integration of renewable resources. These resources lead to a reduction in mechanical inertia but also provide increased flexibility in frequency responses. Namely, their power electronic interfaces can implement almost arbitrary control laws. To design these controllers, reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a powerful method in searching for optimal non-linear control policy parameterized by neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key challenge is to enforce that a learned controller must be stabilizing. This paper proposes a Lyapunov regularized RL approach for optimal frequency control for transient stability in lossy networks. Because the lack of an analytical Lyapunov function, we learn a Lyapunov function parameterized by a neural network. The losses are specially designed with respect to the physical power system. The learned neural Lyapunov function is then utilized as a regularization to train the neural network controller by penalizing actions that violate the Lyapunov conditions. Case study shows that introducing the Lyapunov regularization enables the controller to be stabilizing and achieve smaller losses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Optimal Frequency Control - A Lyapunov Approach</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The increase in penetration of inverter-based resources provides us with more flexibility in frequency regulation compared to conventional linear droop controllers. Using their power electronic interfaces, inverter-based resources can realize almost arbitrary responses to frequency changes. Reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a popular method to design these nonlinear controllers to optimize a host of objective functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key challenge with RL-based approaches is how to enforce the constraint that the learned controller should be stabilizing. In addition, training these controllers is nontrivial because of the time-coupled dynamics of power systems. In this paper, we propose to explicitly engineer the structure of neural network-based controllers such that they guarantee system stability by design. This is done by constraining the network structures using a well-known Lyapunov function. A recurrent RL architecture is used to efficiently train the controllers. The resulting controllers only use local information and outperform linear droop as well as controllers trained using existing state-of-the-art learning approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
