<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning | Wenqi Cui</title>
    <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/tag/machine-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wenqi-cui.github.io/tag/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Machine Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 08:00:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/media/icon_hud58c95a75c7ebfda2aff7ad5a2db624a_15115_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/tag/machine-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few-Shot Machine Learning Classification of Electron Microscopy Data</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/few-shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/few-shot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a UW-DIRECT capstone project cooperated with Pacific Northwest National Laboratory (PNNL) and mentored by Marjolein Oostrom, Sarah Akers and Dr. Steven R. Spurgeon.
We proposed a few-Shot machine learning algorithum for classification of
electron microscopy images and implemented a graphical-user interface for it.
I am responsible for implementing training loop for few-shot machine learning analysis of electron microscope data. 
Transfer learning is utilized to improvement performance of resent on feature extraction of microscope images. The abstract is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent growth in data volumes produced by modern electron microscopes requires rapid, scalable, and flexible approaches to image segmentation and analysis. Few-shot machine learning, which can richly classify images from a handful of user-provided examples, is a promising route to high-throughput analysis. However, current command-line implementations of such approaches can be slow and unintuitive to use, lacking the real-time feedback necessary to perform effective classification. Here we report on the development of a Python-based graphical user interface that enables end users to easily conduct and visualize the output of few-shot learning models. This interface is lightweight and can be hosted locally or on the web, providing the opportunity to reproducibly conduct, share, and crowd-source few-shot analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyapunov-Regularized Reinforcement Learning for Power System Transient Stability</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/lyapunov-regularized-reinforcement-learning-for-power-system-transient-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/lyapunov-regularized-reinforcement-learning-for-power-system-transient-stability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Transient stability of power systems is becoming increasingly important because of the growing integration of renewable resources. These resources lead to a reduction in mechanical inertia but also provide increased flexibility in frequency responses. Namely, their power electronic interfaces can implement almost arbitrary control laws. To design these controllers, reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a powerful method in searching for optimal non-linear control policy parameterized by neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key challenge is to enforce that a learned controller must be stabilizing. This paper proposes a Lyapunov regularized RL approach for optimal frequency control for transient stability in lossy networks. Because the lack of an analytical Lyapunov function, we learn a Lyapunov function parameterized by a neural network. The losses are specially designed with respect to the physical power system. The learned neural Lyapunov function is then utilized as a regularization to train the neural network controller by penalizing actions that violate the Lyapunov conditions. Case study shows that introducing the Lyapunov regularization enables the controller to be stabilizing and achieve smaller losses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Seattle - Prediction and Visualization</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/greem-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/greem-seattle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Green Seattle is an inter-disciplinary project in Clearn Energy Insitute (CEI) collaborated by seven students majoring in Chemical Sciences, 
Political Science and Electrical Engineering. The first part of Green Seattle is focused on predicting Seattle Traffic Trends 
(codes are publicly available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greening-Seattle/Prediction&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), 
while the second is focused on Visualizing Seattle Traffic Trends, 
as well as outputs of a regression model seeking to predict future traffic patterns based on user inputs
(codes are publicly available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Greening-Seattle/Visualization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). 
I am responsible for implementing machine learning framework for predicting Traffic Trends using Tensorflow 2.0,
and visualizing the model in TensorBoard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Optimal Frequency Control - A Lyapunov Approach</title>
      <link>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenqi-cui.github.io/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The increase in penetration of inverter-based resources provides us with more flexibility in frequency regulation compared to conventional linear droop controllers. Using their power electronic interfaces, inverter-based resources can realize almost arbitrary responses to frequency changes. Reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a popular method to design these nonlinear controllers to optimize a host of objective functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key challenge with RL-based approaches is how to enforce the constraint that the learned controller should be stabilizing. In addition, training these controllers is nontrivial because of the time-coupled dynamics of power systems. In this paper, we propose to explicitly engineer the structure of neural network-based controllers such that they guarantee system stability by design. This is done by constraining the network structures using a well-known Lyapunov function. A recurrent RL architecture is used to efficiently train the controllers. The resulting controllers only use local information and outperform linear droop as well as controllers trained using existing state-of-the-art learning approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
